<u>F</u>	ormat of Bio-data in respect of persons desirous of inclusion in DPE databank
1.	Name and surname (in full) <u>SUTANU</u> <u>BEHURIA</u>
2.	Director Identification Number (refer Note 1) 000 5 1 668
3.	Income Tax PAN: ABLPB 1647A
4.	Gender MALE 4. Nationality IDDIAN
5.	Father's name and mother's name and Spouse's name (if married)  LATE NRUSINGS CHARAN BEHURIA (FATHER), LATE SOTT. SWARNALATA  SOTT. PARVINDER BEHURIA (WIFE)  REHURIA (OGTHER)
6.	Date of Birth BULY, 1954
7.	Present Position/Occupation RETIRE) SELRETARY, GOVI. OF INDIA.

8. Full address (present and permanent) with PIN code, Phone number, Mobile Number, E-Mail address)

C19 HUNAYUN ROAD, NEW-DELHI-110003 (PRESENT) 421-B. Poulet'A', Beta-I, Greater Noida-201308, U.P. (Permanent)
98-74-05935, 24641229

9. Educational & Professional Qualification (Graduation onwards)

S.No.	Course	Subjects	University/Institute	Year of
		ļ		Passing
1.	B.A. (HONS).	ECONOTICS.	DELH,	1973
2.	M.V.	t LONOMICA	DELHI	1175
3.	Ph. 0.	EWNONICS	SOUTHERN METHODIST,	1982

. Work	Experience ( 2.v.	allaches )		
S.No.	Organization/	Post Held	Period (From - To)	Nature of
	Institute			Work/Area of
 				Specialization
t	GOVI. OF INDIA	240 , YJ38	Amil 2013 - July 2014	Policy formakli, Alm.
2_	GOVT, OF INDIA	SELY NIWORITY AF	Faces, Sept. 2012 - April 2013	Diverty Wellow
3	GOVT, OF INDIA		Nov. 2011 - Aug. 2012	
પ્	GOV1.8FINDIA	SECY, FERTILISON	Sept. 2010 - Nov. 204	Policy fromtation, Adm

11. Whether SC/ST/OBC/Minorities/Women \_\_\_\_\_ (if yes, indicate the relevant category)

12	Administration,	cialization (Finance, Research, Corporate , Administration	Law, Management, Sales, Marketing Governance, Technical Operations or any
13	Indicate how Rehined Seen experience a	you fulfill the wary to Crut of	laid down criteria (Refer Annex India with 20 years administrativallerd and above.
	. (a) Have any leg		ed or are pending against you : <del>Yes</del> /No
15.	<del>Yes</del> /No	en or are designated p	eartner in limited liability partnerships (LLP)
	Name of LLP 1.	Nature of industry	Duration (with dates)
1.1.1.4.	2. 3.		

16. Directorship held/presently being in companies (both CPSEs and Private) NIL

Name	of	Nature	of	Nature	of	Duration	(with
company		industry		directorship		dates)	( , , , , , , , , , , , , , , , , , , ,
1.							<del></del>
2.							
3.							

1 ImBelini (Signature)

Name SUTANU BEHYRIA

Date 9 Supt. 2014.

Note 1: In case, you are not having Director Identification Number (DIN), you should immediately get the same in line with provisions of Sections 152 to 159 of the Companies Act, 2013 and furnish the updated bio-data to DPE.

Note 2: In case there is any change in the above position, the revised and updated biodata may be furnished to DPE within 15 days of such change.

# **CURRICULUM VITAE**

1. Name : Sutanu Behuria

2. Date of Birth : 2<sup>nd</sup> July 1954

3. Father's Name : Shri Nrusinha Charan Behuria

4. Contact detail : C-1/9, Humayun Road

New Delhi – 110 003 Res. : (11) – 24640667 Mobile: 9871105935

E mail: <u>sutanu2911@yahoo.com</u> <u>sutanu2911@gmail.com</u>

### 5. Academic Qualification:

Institution	University	Degree obtained/ completion date
Stewart School, Bhubaneswar, Orissa, India		Indian School Certificate (1970)
St. Stephens College, Delhi India	Delhi	Bachelor of Arts in Economics (1973)
Delhi School of Economics Delhi, India	Delhi	Master of Arts in Economics (1975)
Southern Methodist University, Dallas, Texas USA	Southern Methodist	Master of Arts in Economics (1981)
Southern Methodist University, Dallas, Texas, USA	Southern Methodist	Ph.D. in Economics (1982)

## 6. Employment History:

	Post Held	Period	Job Description (in brief)
(a)	Secretary, Department of Heavy Industry, Ministry of Heavy Industries & Public Enterprises	April 2, 2013 - 31.07.2014	Administrative head of the Department. Involved in the re-organization and revival of public sector enterprises

			with appropriate packages. The work of Secretary (Heavy Industry) also involves ensuring the formulation of an appropriate policy frame work for the automobile sector and the capital goods sector.
(a)	Secretary, Ministry of Minority Affairs	September 1, 2012 – April 1, 2013	Administrative head of the Ministry. Responsible for implementing various schemes for the welfare and development of minorities including education, employment creation and provision of basic services and credit.
(b)	Secretary, National Disaster Management Authority, Ministry of Home Affairs, Government of India	November 2, 2011 – August 31, 2012	Responsible for policy formulation, responsible for policies regarding preparedness, mitigation, response and rehabilitation in the context of disasters in the country.
(c)	Secretary, Department of Fertilizers, Ministry of Chemicals & Fertilizers, Government of India	September 1, 2010 — November,2011	Administratively in-charge of the Department of Fertilizers. The main task is to ensure timely availability of fertilizers to the farmers at an affordable price. Consequently, it involves monitoring of production and import as well as its transportation. From the financial angle, the main effort is to restrict the subsidy outgo.
(d)	Special Secretary & Financial Advisor, Department of Commerce, Ministry of Textiles, in Government of India	November 24, 2009 - September, 2010	Financial Management of the budget of the Ministries. Board member of MMTC, STC, NTC and NJMC, JCI, ITPO, T.N. TPO, Karnataka

			TPO, W.B. TPO, NIFT, IIFT. Participated in FTAs which included the auto sector.
( e)	Additional Secretary & Financial Advisor, Department of Commerce, Ministry of Textiles, in Government of India	May, 2007 to 23, November 2009	Financial Management of the budget of the Ministries. Board member of MMTC, STC, NTC and NJMC, JCI, ITPO, T.N. TPO, Karnataka TPO, W.B. TPO, NIFT, IIFT
(f)	Principal Secretary (Finance, Planning, Economics & Statistics), Government of Himachal Pradesh	December, 2005 to April, 2007	Management of the State finances. Prepared the State budget for 2006-07 and 2007-08. Initiated policy reforms and finalized the Development Policy Loan for US\$200 million with the World Bank.
(g)	Senior Policy Adviser (Commonwealth Fund for Technical Corporation) Ministry of Finance, Government of Mauritius	November, 2003 to November, 2005	Advise on macro-economic management and policies. Train government officials in macro-economic policy formulation and advise on dealings with international organizations including World Bank and IMF.
(h)	Joint Secretary & Financial Adviser Ministry of Coal & Ministry of Mines, Government of India	March, 2000 to November, 2003	Financial Management of the two Ministry's budgets. As a member of the Board of PSUs in the coal and minerals sectors responsible for financial restructuring and privatization. The PSUs included Coal India, National Aluminum, Neyveli Lignite etc.
(i)	Secretary (Public Works, Town & Country Planning Departments), H.P. Government	June, 1998 to March, 2000	Responsible for overall administration of the Departments. In Public Works, responsible for formulation of policy regarding user charges, private sector participation, EIA etc. especially in the

	·		context of World Bank assistance. In Town & Country Planning formulated policies regarding development of township in ecologically sensitive areas and housing for economically weaker sections.
(j)	Development & Welfare), H.P. Government	November 1 <b>997</b> , to May, 1998	Responsible for formulating State government policies on poverty alleviation, gender issues, participatory development, capacity building of grass root functionaries and decentralization of planning.
(k)	Chief Electoral Officer, H.P. Government	December 1995, to November, 1997	Responsible for conducting free and fair elections in the State.
(1)	Member (Finance & Accounts) H.P. State Electricity Board	December 1994, to November, 1995	Overall in-charge of financial management of the Electricity Board. Also, responsible for formulating policies for private sector participation in the Power Sector.
(m)	Programme Officer/ Economist (China, Central Asian Republics) Asian Development Bank, Manila, Philippines	June 1994, to December, 1994	Preparation of the first economic report for Kazakhstan as well as the policy based Special Assistance Loan. Preparation of Social Safety Net strategies for Kazakhstan. Responsible for policy-based lending programmes in Health, Environment and Education Sectors for the People's Republic of China. Participated in preparation of the poverty alleviation strategy for People's Republic of China.

(n)	Programme Officer/Economist (Indonesia, Malaysia), Asian Development Bank, Manila, Philippines	June, 1991 to May, 1994	Responsible for preparation of annual economic reports. Responsible for policy level discussions with the Governments on cost recovery, private sector participation and capacity building. Prepared the poverty alleviation strategy and the Micro credit project.
(0)	Director's Assistant Executive Director for India, Bangladesh, Vietnam, Bhutan and Lao PDR, Asian Development Bank, Manila, Philippines	June, 1989 to May, 1991	Preparation of papers on development prospects of the constituent countries. Formulation of papers on the need for concessional funding from the Asian Development Fund. Presentation of the view of DMCs for restructuring with a human face.
(p)	Deputy Secretary, Department of Economic Affairs, Ministry of Finance, Government of India	April, 1987 to June, 1989	Operational Officer for bilateral aid programmes of the EEC and its constituent countries as well as the Asian Development Bank. Sectorally responsible for Rural Development Health and Education. Formulated the present discounting method and pre-financing policy. Negotiated the social projects with the donors.
(q)	Deputy Commissioner and District Magistrate, Solan, H.P.	June, 1984 to April, 1987	Overall in-charge of district administration. Implementation of poverty alleviation projects besides the other development programmes.
(r)	Deputy Commissioner and District Magistrate, Bilaspur, H.P.	October, 1983 to June, 1984	Overall in-charge of district administration. Implementation of poverty alleviation projects besides

			the other development programmes.
(s)	Managing Director, Himachal Wool Processors & Himachal Worsted Mills Ltd., H.P.	August, 1982 to September, 1983	Chief Executive Office of two Public Sector Units. Corporate planning, financial management including formulation of a plan for disinvestment and sale.
(t)	Teaching Assistant, Department of Economics, Southern Methodist University, Dallas, Texas, U.S.A.	August, 1979 to July, 1982	Teaching macro-economic theory to undergraduates. Research in economics.
(u)	Sub-Divisional Officer, Kullu, H.P.	July, 1978 to July, 1979	Overall in-charge of district administration. Implementation of poverty alleviation projects besides the other development programmes.
(v)	Officer Trainee, LBS Academy of Administration, Mussoorie	June, 1976 to June, 1978	Training in Administration
(w)	Lecturer in Economics, St. Stephen's College, Delhi	June, 1975 to June, 1976	Teaching macro-economic theory and public finance.

#### 7. Prizes and Scholarships:

(a)	Phi Beta Kappa, Southern Methodist University, Dallas, Texas, USA (1982)
(b)	Rudra Economics Prize, St. Stephen's College, Delhi (1973)
(c)	Advanced Center Scholarship, Delhi School of Economics, Delhi (1983-75)

#### 8. Languages known:

- English Hindi Oriya French (a)
- (b)
- (c)
- (d)

### 9. Research:

Dissertation: (a) The Household Demand for Money Uncertainty: Theory and Evidence, Ph.D. Thesis, Southern Methodist University, Dallas, Texas, USA. (b) Other "Taxation and Employment in General Equilibrium: A Research: Two Sector Analysis" Journal of Development Economics. 14 (1984): 219-239. "The incidence of the Corporation Income Tax when Labour Supply is Variable: A General Equilibrium Analysis" Working Paper No, 138, Southern Methodist University, Dallas, Texas, U.S.A. "A Theory of the Firm with Financial Activities", Working Paper No, 157, Southern Methodist University, Dallas, Texas, U.S.A., Co-Authors: T. Fomby and J. Hadar. "Taxation and Employment in General Equilibrium: A Theoretical and Empirical Analysis" Working Paper No. 145, Southern Methodist University, Dallas, Texas, U.S.A. "The Role of Intermediate Services in Economic Development: The Malaysian Example", Occasional Paper No. 8, Asian Development Bank, Co-Author: Rahul Khullar. "Some Aspects of Land Administration in Indonesia: Implications for Bank Operations", Occasional Paper No. 10, Asian Development Bank.